Diego Taveras

Copiague, NY 11726 - (631) 836-1033

<u>Diegotaveras.dev@gmail.com</u> - <u>linkedin.com/in/diegotaveras/</u> - <u>github.com/diegodjty</u> - <u>.diegotaveras.com/</u>

Front-End Developer with experience creating intuitive and visually appealing websites. Possess years of experience designing and implementing responsive web pages utilizing HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, as well as modern libraries and frameworks such as React and Next. I am a positive communicator and excel at working collaboratively with crossfunctional teams to bring projects to life. Capable at collaborating with cross-functional teams to bring projects from concept to completion.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

FREELANCE WEB DEVELOPER,

Copiague, NY

Html5, Css3, JavaScript, TailwindCSS, NextJS, React, StyledComponents

Jan 2020-Present

- Managed cross-functional communications with hosting companies, clients, and vendors, both verbally and in writing.
- Organized and led client meetings to review websites and gather detailed specifications for new and existing projects.
- Boost website performance, achieving a score of 95+ through optimization and redesign efforts.
- Created innovative front-end designs using HTML5, CSS3, and ReactJS.
- Managed Google Business profiles for clients, resulting in a 50% increase in interactions and overall online presence.
- Developed websites from scratch, fully responsive and pixel perfect from figma Designs.

REACT JOB SIMULATOR,

Copiague, NY

React, TypeScript, NextJs, Styled Components, Cypress, StoryBook

Nov 2021-Present

- Built features and fixed bugs in the ProLog codebase during the React Job Simulator program.
- Used advanced workflow with ESLint, Prettier, TypeScript, Husky, CI with GitHub Actions, and Trunk-Based Development with Pull Requests as Git workflow.
- Fixed bugs in existing code and added new features based on Kanban tasks and Figma designs.
- Discussed and enhance code after code reviews by senior developer.

FRONT END DEVELOPER INTERN, FARMINGDALE STATE COLLEGE.

Farmingdale, NY

React, D3.js, Apex Charts, Styled Components

SEP 2020-DEC 2020

- Developed user-friendly interfaces using ReactJS, resulting in improved user experience and satisfaction.
- Created eye-catching and interactive visualizations utilizing Apex Charts, enhancing overall design and functionality.
- Implemented client-side email functionality using EmailJS, resulting in a 90% decrease in the time required for communication and increasing overall efficiency.
- Manipulated data to create dynamic and informative documents using D3.js, resulting in an average 100% increase in the ability for users to understand complex information.
- Optimized web pages for speed and scalability, resulting in faster load times and enhanced user experience.

FRONT END DEVELOPER INTERN, FARMINGDALE STATE COLLEGE

Farmingdale, NY May 2019–Dec 2019

React, Styled Components

• Crafted interfaces using ReactJS, contributing to an elevated user experience.

- Converted the application into a seamless Single Page Application using React-Router.
- Designed and implemented a flexible Drag-and-Drop sortable component for organizing complex nested data with react-sortable-tree.
- Styled and maintained the responsive design of the site using SASS, ensuring optimal viewing on all devices.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, including designer, back-end developer, project manager.

EDUCATION

FARMINGDALE STATE COLLEGE, Bachelor of Science in Computer Programming and Information System (concentration: Web Development).

Farmingdale, NY Jul 2021

INFOTEP, Technician In Computer Science.

Dominican Republic

Nov 2016

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Html5, Css3, JavaScript, jQuery, TypeScript, Redux, React, NextJS, PHP, MySQL, NodeJS, Python, Bootstrap, Tailwind, SASS, Git, JSON, AJAX, Sequealize, Mongoose, Cypress, Netlify, Heroku, Vercel, AWS.
- Fluent in English, Spanish.